# GRAHAM BAKER

# graham.cr.baker@gmail.com

Passionate, curious, always engaging new ideas and bring enthusiasm to everything. For the past five years, worked as a professional musician, producing five full-length records on two record labels and performing on six nationwide tours playing almost 400 shows along the way. In addition to creative work, took charge of administrative and business duties that included creating a web presence, designing and producing merchandise, and coordinating performances. Excited to bring the same energy and dedication to the work of a data scientist.

## Work Experience

### Data Science Career Track Bootcamp at Springboard

Feburary 2019 - Present

- Studying Statistics, Data Cleaning, Data Visualization, and Machine Learning
- Using Python, pandas, numpy, scikit-learn, apache spark, SQL, seaborn, matplotlib, jupyter notebooks
- Created Capstone project that predicted success of Kickstarter Campaigns. Used random forest on numeric values and naive bayes for NLP ensembled together to produce high precision and recall on predictions
- Mentored by Sr. Data Scientist in weekly meetings that included code reviews, industry insight, and discussions on advanced topics in Data Science

#### Lead Teacher at Creative Coding 4 Kids, Seattle, WA

January 2016 - May 2018

- Taught classes of 10-20 students the basics of object-oriented programming using Scratch
- Designed a curriculum and supervised support teachers to implement in the classroom
- Directed communication with parents of students via newsletters and one-on-one conversations

#### Software Developer at Peer Market Exchange, Tacoma, WA October 2014 - May 2015

- Developed a platform for Blockchain-powered financial instuments using MongoDB, Ember, Angular, and Node to be issued and traded
- Utilized open-source libraries to create wallets, initiate transactions, and track assets
- Studied ecosystem surrounding bitcoin, including peer-to-peer technologies, crytography, and security

#### Education

#### University of Puget Sound

Tacoma, WA United States, May 2015

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

- Relevant Coursework: Software Engineering, Algorithms, Database Management, Computer Architecture, Network Programming
- Notable Projects: MiniJava Compiler, Peer-to-Peer Website Hosting Platform, E-Commerce website (MEAN stack)

#### Bachelor of Arts in Business Administration

- Relevant Coursework: Marketing, Management, Accounting, Law and Ethics of Business, Social Entrepreneurship, Finance
- Notable Projects: Emminent Domain Research Paper regarding Keystone Pipeline, Study on the Ethics of the Gig Economy